ladies and gentlemen welcome to the
junkyard live podcast today I have Bryan
DJ toasty and Kelly Kells that's what
have you both here so this one I'm
pretty pumped about we have the three of
us here and we are all three DJs we've
all been DJs for like quite a while in
different areas and different fields and
we've crossed different paths in
different ways so I want to just kind of
like start from the inside and and
branch out and kind of explain our world
of DJing from from this side of the
decks you know so I think I'm gonna
start I want to ask you guys about how
you got started with DJing so I'm gonna
start with that I'll tell kind of my
intro story so Kelly knows it very well
i toast you if you didn't know I got
into DJing through Kelly he we had met
up through a mutual friend and we were
just BS in about I mean I seem to be
like Bassnectar or something that I
don't really like that much know how
good but so we just got bonding over
that and I just like I have this
opportunity I was like man like DJing
was so cool and you were just like what
that's so cool that you think that let
me show you everything and I was like
yeah I mean I was probably crying my
night I was so pumped because I you know
I just thought you know you didn't think
that when you think about this art form
DJing
even yeah any art form you think that
there's like gatekeepers and like you
feel kind of embarrassed to ask about it
right so but anyway so you so we can
touch on that certainly but you made me
feel super comfortable over the next few
months you had showed me a couple thing
I came over to your house and you then
let me borrow you then let me borrow
your mixer for a couple months and that
was like I mean that's like the rest of
my life I definitely sent me down the
path so I definitely am grateful for
that
so Kelly started me out here but so
before that when I have like just
flirted with it I actually had this
moment at the gorge before I had asked
you before whatever even gave me the
courage to ask you to show me I had this
moment at the gorge where I was watching
cascade on the hill and I was by myself
and my friends had floated off and it
was just this like euphoric moment where
it was like
if I could do something make it maybe I
can make people feel how he's making me
feel oh is this like I'm wonder if and
then that's when I kind of decided that
that I wanted to flirt with the world of
DJing to making music so that was my
like falling in love with the art of of
DJing in music and Kelly you skyrocketed
me out there then from there it was just
the history behind that a big DJing for
eight years I think no something like
that um and that's just expanded to
everything we started with EDM and then
I just play a little bit of everything
now you go into clubs and bars and
weddings and ctsos and corporate events
and stuffy stuff have DJed a funeral one
so that was strange
yeah oh no it's a wake we have to call
it awake because that's that means not
funeral made actually really wasn't that
bad but anyway the the point being is we
all kind of get into DJing in our art
forms in different ways so there's kind
of a little step in the water of how I
got mine so let's go ahead and go to you
cows what what did you get started DJing
and in like what even led you to to take
that step towards it so I moved up to
Bellingham when I was I was right out of
high school moved up there and just kind
of you know sat down with a few of my
friends and really hey we know this cool
Google bar you want to go so I went down
there is this list hole in the wall it's
called the Cobra lounge and this guy
walked in there and really cool like
murals on the wall like couches
everywhere who like hookah lounge pretty
cool right this guy named DJ Einstein
was well yeah very cool name was
spinning that night and he just the way
he be Jade like made everything just so
cool and just so dynamic and it was a
cool environment it was just like wow
like this is really cool like
I want to do that kind of thing you know
and and from there I just kind of
researched it and I saved up a little
bit money for some speakers and my first
mixer and yeah it went from there
and then we we had this big a bedroom
house as a duplex and we had parties
every once in a while and they're always
like Kelly your games we're gonna play
tonight I'm like yeah why not let's do
it yeah so just kind of got started
there and then yeah I yeah just really
snowballed from there like doors open up
right you start mean to hit different
gigs yeah so eventually I think what was
I was at that point where you're still
they were sold vinyls being played -
mm-hmm wait you remember like what
year-ish this was oh wait hell D I'm 30
yeah 30 okay yeah - you're sort of me so
finals yeah that's crazy because I like
skipped over vitals I guess - like
really like timestamp it is like right
when Rosco came out like boob us got me
into dubstep you know that's crazy my
first show that got me into even
enjoying EDM was was Rosco yeah yeah so
I just remember you're like even being
in the back room and this this person
actually played a big part of it - his
name was Greg Jones and him and his
buddy David were DJs and Greg's Greg and
I are in the back room over where I was
working at the time and he goes dude
have you ever heard this and you know
there was like Houseman is there's like
Daft Punk and like justice and all those
kind of guys that were out so I was kind
of some of those and that kind of got me
into that but then finally it like I've
never heard of this like what the what
what is this like and it just got me
hooked
so yeah dubstep and DJing kinda just
went hand in hand and I kind of took off
from there so one house party led to
another house party I think I did it for
like there was a house party after house
party for like three months straight
of course it just that
I've got me like kind of like help me I
don't know how to say it like just get
better yeah DJ forces you to learn I
mean throws you have the wolf and it's
like perform in your yes so try owner
you know and yeah that's came home met
you
yeah and Khan the rest is history yeah
we started doing some bigger shows and
say yeah well okay dope cool dad that's
DJ Kells and so now we got toasty DJ
toasty man give me some of your
background I really don't even know the
ledge oh my gosh man you guys gonna make
me feel old so so I actually started
DJing in 95 so I was in a high or so I
started because we had mobile DJ's
coming in and doing our high school
dances and they were older and they're
like way older like 30 plus and so they
were playing music that I mean really
wasn't connecting with anybody and so I
you know I said I could do that and it's
funny you know now I think back and I
got into it too because I'd go to the
high school dances and I was kind of the
outcast I didn't dance you know it was
very awkward I love music classically
trained piano saxophone bassoon trombone
played all those instruments growing up
but I you know I didn't like the music
that the guy was playing and I didn't I
couldn't dance so it was like okay well
I want to go to these functions because
that's part of that whole social you
know growth thing how am I going to be
still involved and so I hooked up with
the guy locally Scott knelling who owns
music more deejays great guy and I said
hey you know I I don't have the music
library cuz in 95 yet there wasn't the
Internet there wasn't like you just go
to Spotify or you know yeah you could
you couldn't just go buy music I mean
sorry you couldn't go quote fine music
you actually had to have a collection
and so he hooked me up he said yeah I'll
let you rent my
my mobile gig set up and so we had way
too many speakers and blew too many
Breakers the next dance and it was it
was amazing it was so much fun
so that was 95 starred graduated high
school went off to college for a little
bit came back and there was a place that
opened up in town it's on the corner of
Commerce and Florida right now it's the
Roxy coffee that whole building used to
be called South Pacific so that was like
2002 2005 and so I went in there and
they it was funny because they had
started with with house music because
that's what the owners liked and it was
way before the EDM boom and so nobody in
town nobody one in your house music and
so they'd had like two DJ's that were
just working it and good DJ's fantastic
deejays and I loved it I went in there a
couple times I'm like oh my god this is
you know it was fantastic and I had
started listening to I grew up you know
listening an alternative music you know
grunge and STP and and Allison chains
and Red Hot Chili Peppers in that whole
Nirvana that whole age of grunge but I'd
really got into like eurodance it's
gonna sound cheesy saying it but vanga
boys and to unlim and you know that
whole pop house for your cheesy pop yeah
I mean you know Chemical Brothers you
know that whole genre of music just
prodigy so I just I fell in love with
that type of music but there was no
place to play it there was no place to
listen to it there wasn't online mixes
back then you know
so anyway stumbled into to this South
Pacific and they had these house DJ's
loved it but there was nobody there
they're all over at the casino with next
door because there did top 40 pop over
there and so I talked to the owners and
I said hey you know I'm a mobile DJ and
you know I'll play any type of music you
want to play and they're like yeah we'll
give you a shot so start playing there
and just did kind of an open format
wedding reception mix music and at the
end of the night the last 30 minutes I'd
always play house and the people that
wanted to listen the house we're
there you know and if the people that
didn't want to listen the house and they
just kind of trickle out the front door
and it was okay the owners were cool
with it so did that got hooked up with a
concept entertainment so that place
close to no.5 2005 then got hooked up
concept entertainment became their music
director and oversaw music programming
for seven different locations in
Portland so thirsty lion chain Grand
Central bull Lotus there was a couple
other places but the main one that I was
working out was Barracuda which was the
largest nightclub in the Pacific
Northwest 1,100 person capacity on
average deejaying between 8 and 15
hundred people sometimes we push
capacities so that was definitely a
getting thrown to the wolves because
South Pacific was like 200 people max
and you have different different room
sizes have definitely different energies
different speed of mixing just different
skill sets yeah and honestly a 1100
person room is a lot easier to DJ for
than like 150 percent room you know
because they're all there 11 other
people they're not going anywhere you
can get away with whatever you want to
play and so that you know somebody enjoy
it because that's what the crowds need
someone to give them permission to dance
I mean that's not a lot of crowds works
yep if there's one part even one grifoll
you can get 30 people happy out of a
huge group like that you get every seven
yeah so did that for a while they ended
up shifting their focus and expanding
their thirsty lion brand which is a
gastropub design and so they actually
closed Burcu CUDA and I closed a couple
of the other locations that were just
high risk meaning liquor sales as
opposed to food sales and so they close
those down I made a career change got
into IT at that time but have still kind
of dabbled in I had a residency over and
Bend for three years and was doing that
once a month
do a lot of consulting for sound
installs and promotions and marketing so
I kind of get to keep my toes in the
nightclub piece of it but not be out
late you know past 9:00 p.m. and still
get to getting involved with the local
scene here with you guys kind of
dabbling back into what I really love
but obviously it's not my full-time gig
anymore yeah so I mean yeah it's dead
it's funny how it's you start with one
thing and it rejects you on to all these
other things that because that's how I
started with my audio engineering an
audio directing stuff is I was like met
up with Kelly and I was like music is
cool right and then it was like DJing is
cool and then it was after that it was
kind of like the the production company
that I've been doing just random
whatever like Heil rap chords like just
teach me I work a camera I'll do it you
know it's doing like all these side
things it was fine like oh cool I have
like I am pretty good you know I'm
getting good of this music thing I could
start making this kind of my specialty
and so I drove into that sounds like
what you did that too um I want to think
forgive me you guys it's history that's
great I want to back up a little bit
from the moment that we like first got
into DJing right I I can't talk about
what you guys see as different so
imagine where our 16 year old selves
where our you know or whatever age we
were when we were like thinking like
what if I could DJ what if I could
whatever it's so different now than it
was back then like like we had our own
struggles and we found a way like I mean
ours ours seems like cakewalk to you
because you had to really search them
yeah though so the you know it's funny I
was thinking about this on the drive
over that you talk about gatekeeping
right you know like you needed to meet
somebody in order to be able to get into
that that world and for me I a guy his
name's Aaron he's a couple years older
than me and he was really in the house
music and he had turntables right so the
the things that are different for like a
DJ trying to get started now from back
then back then to buy to use turntables
and a mixer it was like seven
50 bucks meaning used and it was garbage
stuff right but then to be able to
actually get the music so talking about
vinyl right so an import a UK import
house record might have three tracks on
it was 1199 1099 up at platinum down in
Portland so to be able to even inquire
the music because you couldn't get it
anywhere else besides on vinyl most the
times or you can find it on CD this is
before limelight wire so you couldn't
even pirate it right for a domestic so
if you wanted to you know get 50 cent in
the club and you had to buy two of them
because you'd wear them out seriously oh
yeah that's a thing to wait wait hold on
how do you wear that I don't know much
about my know this so so you know your
needle you when you're cueing you're
actually cutting a little bit off the
song each time and every time that it
plays through it's not digital it's not
just reading ones and zeros you know
it's it's reading the the bumps and the
groove so that that needle digs into it
and it'll actually the more times that
you play it the the less sonic quality
that record will have and finally and
then just you know being drunk back in
my early days you'd skip skip a needle
and you'd scratch cross and then it was
junk because it would click each time
that it would come around so you'd have
to have to to be able to you know if it
was a hot song and those were five bucks
and they might have one or two tracks on
it so this was you know 23 years ago it
was just it was super expensive to be
able to even get into DJing you could go
out and buy the single on like a CD you
could buy someone's album right but if
you're mixing if you're doing an eight
beat mix you can't mix the singles yeah
so it was it was challenging you know
your guys's challenges are way different
than what mine were you know when I
started definitely yeah I think too much
like one of my challenges is I mean you
said it's like oh I got like I have
these banger songs like oh no I got to
get him I mean it's probably you could
probably play that out for a while or
there was chances where people wouldn't
really hear that song unless you had
like you bright show them yeah and that
was that was a any other challenge that
you'd have is you know
you'd show up to a gig and you pack two
crates right so crate has between
depending on the size crate 40 to 70
tracks on it right so you'd show up and
you have 80 to 140 tracks that's it
right and so if the crowd wasn't feeling
what you were playing you're kind of in
a corner yeah cuz you couldn't go
anywhere like you know you if you're if
you had a multi-hour gig not just a
one-hour gig show up you know be the
stud but if you had like an open to
closed type set and you started playing
your tracks and people showing up and
like oh I don't like this type of thing
you know if they're expecting hip-hop or
top 40 in your playing house you're kind
of stuck I mean that's yeah I mean
that'd be devastating I could like I'm
always you know cuz you're always
watching the room you're like okay they
don't like this right we gotta go
somewhere else yeah there's there's part
of like you know you got to kind of push
what you were hired for a lot of times
you got to dig into like what's really
going on what you kind of want to push
them into what's gonna happen in the
coming hours yeah you can't just give
them exactly what they want but man I
couldn't imagine that being looks like
grab a playlist or like all right I'm
totally in the bed I'm going to
just like look up Spotify for ideas
right and then once I get the ideas I
can even download it so that's something
I could even download it on the fly yeah
you couldn't even like you didn't have
the option of like well that's a whole
crate I left that says genre I left in
the crate at home right and even touch
on it well and I and I think that you
know some of the crowd challenges that
we were talking about earlier I you know
the the thing with the crowds is that
they have their Spotify list that
they've been listening to before they
even get to the club like I want to hear
that so I think some of you know when we
can touch on that more later but yeah I
mean I definitely do want to touch on
that I mean that's something that that I
think I'm talk to both you guys about is
the I've noticed in the last few years
that I'm you know my job is more
difficult like that sentence just kind
of sucks but crowds are more difficult
to please they want what they want right
now because that's what they're used to
I mean we're all like that to start some
extent but I'm like really taking a like
how is it different from when I first
started when I
from now and then hearing you too it's
like the people's reaction to okay I
don't like this song no okay but carry
about my life you know like oh that
sucks like oh maybe this isn't place for
us let's go somewhere else me this isn't
our drama of music tonight let's go
somewhere else
now that person is like they're so used
to being able to pull out their phone
and change the song they don't stop him
didn't stop themselves but they're just
walking up to the stage it's like their
body is just moving them and they're
like hey can you play this song or can
you play something else or they'll say
something like blatantly rude over the
last few years I personally feel that
people have gotten I mean I'm gonna say
50% more mean towards towards the dude
on the stage maybe that's just been a
lot of my experience I definitely don't
want like paint a corner that like
everyone's mean to DJ's now you know I'm
not trying to cry about it but um it's I
don't know I think that the technology
and people in the crowd knowing more
about music knowing more about thinking
they know a lot more about our jobs in
coming and like demanding things I
definitely touched on that Kelly have
you noticed any like you've been doing
it for a while - I mean and we've kind
of been in similar crowds we've played a
lot of the same places have you noticed
any like the last few years you know any
technology kind of changing the way
people definitely definitely you know I
am a primary user of Spotify I think
people like to create their own
playlists and it is very 80 80 d in a
way like when for me like I like to sit
down I listen to listen whol whole album
like just sit down listen to a whole
album and just kind of you know get the
get the feel of things and I if I don't
like a certain song I'll just keep let
it ride just keep playing and I think
you're definitely right like people
people come up to me like hey I want
this song right now or I'm gonna leave
in like five five seconds yeah when
people start figuring out that doesn't
work what why would people people say
that all the time right here's the thing
if you really want your song played give
the DJ some money passing five bucks
over
respect yeah right show up like here's
what you do you show up
you go hey I really like your mix
tonight or hey I really like that sure
that's pretty cool like do you think you
could play this song for me or even like
you say well say that first like you
like compliment them
yeah then like if that doesn't work like
pass them five bucks right see if your
song gets played yeah Arisa well and I
mean that's been since the day of you
know the the dawn of DJing that has
always been requests always always and
you know for me uh you know my residency
and Bend was was amazing because it
allowed me to play basically everything
and you know the crowd was so diverse
there was there's gay and lesbian and
black and Hispanics and whites and it's
just just an awesome mixing pot of
different backgrounds and people
enjoying different music so you can kind
of go everywhere but then you have you
know it's my birthday crowd and they
come up and they want to hear you know
their song right now and and there's a
lot going on when we're DJing you know
we are trying to I equate it to chess
where we've got four or five songs that
we've in our mind were like I want to go
here this is the end point that I want
to get to so you know someone comes up
to you and they're like oh I want this
song and you're at 120 beats per minute
and you're you're trying to get to 130
because and we can go into music theory
and talk about you know trying to rotate
the dance floor and all that but they
come up they're like oh I want this song
and it's it's a hot song right and it's
70 beats per minute and it's like okay
the energy is way up here and then
they're being demanding and they're like
but I want it right now
and you don't want to tell them no
because it's a good song and maybe I'll
get to it
you know and you tell them you know like
yeah a great song I'm gonna get to it
probably in about 45 minutes and they're
like no I want to hear right now he
refused to accept that and yeah like
that they the fact that is an option for
them to come up to the stage say I want
this and we say I'm gonna try it's not
right when you want it and for them to
just walk away and say okay thanks it
seems to me that I'm getting more like
no right I want it
it's a weird thing it is yes so so as
you're talking about BPM you your talk
and I definitely wanna touch on that I
want to describe to you know I think of
listeners who enjoyed eating they enjoy
what we do maybe they know anything
about us but we don't know anything
about teachings right you mentioned BPM
beats per minute and even terminologies
like that I wonder like
unpack so that is something that when a
DJ starts every single song has has a
BPM of beats per minute every song has a
tempo every song has a key has all these
dynamics that it's the DJ's job to
wondering about prior to know about
prior they have to take that song prior
in if they're in in a comfortable spot
they already have all their cues laid
out they know what they're gonna do with
that song they know that that song goes
good with these other songs sometimes if
they're familiar with if it's not brand
new
yes our Kelly that shared this oh my god
[Laughter]
it'd be funny if you were ranting like
some BPM and all these things that that
DJ's to you so if you guys can help me I
would love to without like whining about
this is something that I'm concerned
with it I'm gonna sound like I'm just
like you got to understand when I'm
trying to do back here you know how do
we explain the the art of DJing of disk
jockey of mixing music cuz it's not just
about who can play the most bangers it's
it's not just about the transitions it's
not just about the taste
it's about looking at like glancing
around the room saying where's this
gonna go in ten minutes of work what's
gonna happen what time is it now what's
it gonna look like in 45 minutes there's
like you said beautifully is the chess
game right in and I feel that that the
to me looking forward to the next few
years the crowds if they continue to be
so demanding and not understanding and
not try to like let's just be where
we're at let's try to control this thing
let's just exist and let the DJ do what
they want to do I fear that that we're
not gonna be able to play chess we're
just gonna turn into wonderful solo
Spotify stylish
right so um yeah I don't know any
experiences you guys have or anything
you could think of that's like explains
the part there so the the the phrase
that that I always think in the back of
my mind that a successful DJ is someone
who plays the right song exactly the
right time that's if if I have a night
like that and I have like five or six
points in the night where people just
freak out mm-hm
you've played the the right song and not
freaked out just because I played you
know the top 100 is right right like
people forget about a song and you play
it at the right time like oh my god you
know in the and the dancefloor just goes
and they're just having the time of
their life and you carry that for like
five or six songs right like oh my god I
mean that for me as the DJ is is where
it's at is playing the right song at the
right time because you can play all the
bangers at 9:00 p.m. and that's the
wrong time mm-hmm that's what everybody
requests and that's what they want them
it's weird yeah I want to say like even
even though I going right off the bat
they're just that Einstein guy that DJ
Einstein watching him kind of paint the
room was so cool and I guess that's
that's I think that to me is what it's
about like it's you're right you can
definitely play all the bangers you can
even play stuff no one's even heard of
and in your mind it's like oh yeah this
is gonna go off okay but it doesn't and
you're like what's going on because some
people dude
all right a DJ is kinda like food man
what we're like chefs in a way like
sometimes all you want some greasy
hamburger yeah man that's cupid
shuffle is the basic aim my favorite
when I play locally cuz that's the first
thing that come up in requests you can
play cupid shuffle tonight like you know
what tonight's gonna be special we're
not gonna play cupid shuffle oh and you
see the look in their face they're like
I've been here in the cupid shuffle
every single week for the last three
weeks you know for the last three years
made yeah yeah that's true okay can I
get fold can I confess something real
quick that's it oh my gosh Brian you're
gonna
pay me for this so we we we all want an
agreement that keep it shuffle is just
the bane of our existence right it is so
I got evil one day I got really evil cuz
you cupid shuffle it just repeats itself
right right so what I did I called it I
called it the stupid shuffle and it's
ten minutes long and it's this it's like
the same like over and over so people
like to dance to the song that kind of
line danced it so 10 minutes long
yeah you put it people people out there
for six minutes and they're just like
when's it gonna end I'm like you know
what's so hilarious is man it's so crazy
you just mentioned that because I have
an 8 minute and six seconds I think it's
cha-cha slide yes that I actually did
the other day I was like I gotta go to
the bathroom my friends here I'm gonna
say hi to him really quick so I was like
this is perfect I got like four minutes
that I can be away and so I was walking
around and I was literally thinking at
the end of it they were so enticed at
seven minutes the exact same amount of
enticement that was at one minute and so
I was like I could play this exact same
song and these I still go
into the left back to back just mix into
it yeah alright so so that that's a
great thing to even just lean on so the
reason why you know we're poking fun
because it's our job right the cha-cha
slide the shuffle I'll still play for me
it's yeah by Usher that's like always
the one that I always joke about that
song I hoped it just burns if I ever
invited invent a time machine I'm gonna
skip over cha-cha slide to keep it
shuffle and just delete that like
uh sir but no you know not ya know but
uh so when we say things like it's a lot
of people like I know you hate requests
requests Jake or I know DJ's hate
requests some people kind of get that it
is a request but they know that sentence
right and they know that like they also
come up and they say hey we play the
cupid shuffle like nobody's dancing row
they're like it's gonna get everyone try
to tell you like they try to like bro
trust me with this thing that the credit
person so how do we communicate how do
we explain to them why we don't like
this is a broad example but why we don't
really
like requests and why we don't super
love the line dances for me it's because
I can't do anything with it it's just
hitting play but what what about for you
guys what's that I you know I I'm you
guys might shoot me but I think it's
anything there's two sides to the coin
if I go into a new market okay so like
when I first started going to bend and I
didn't know the market at all right
and so I'm out there and I'm doing my
deal and you know trying to impress
people and people would come up and they
would request stuff and so if you don't
know the market like if you're traveling
you're doing a Northwest circuit or
whatever right people that are coming up
to you and they're like you know I want
this trick or want it you're like okay I
need to probably go in that direction so
it gives you a clue of okay this this is
the type of hip-hop this is the energy
level hip hop that I need to be playing
or a top 40 you know because that's the
type that they're requesting so there
are some good and bad things with it but
the the whole you know I want to hear
this song it's 10 p.m.
there's nobody here it's number one song
in the US whatever it is right they want
to hear it right then you know and a lot
of people consumers maybe don't
understand as DJ's we definitely don't
want to say no but there are a gazillion
songs out there and for us to repeat a
song in a night is ridiculous with the
amount with the amount of songs that are
out there and the hits that have been
out there over the past 20 years it
doesn't I mean there's so many other
songs that you can play besides two
songs in the same night so it makes it
challenging I mean I personally don't
like requests it depends if I'm having a
specialty night you know if we're doing
an EDM only night and they'll come up in
the request and Drake and I'm like you
know the last 15 minutes you've heard
has just been straight house you really
think that I'm gonna be playing Drake
you know or it's billed that way I mean
that's one of the reasons why I started
doing my own nights you know is to throw
my own party and say this is what the
music is so when they walk in the
expectation but yeah I have kind of a
love-hate relationship
with requests I mean going back to the
whole cheeseburger and a steak kind of
thing I mean some people like stick some
some people want a cheeseburger like you
know that shows one cheeseburger every
night yeah so even like even if you have
like the the hottest records in your
mind if you go through your DJ pool if
you follow some of the hottest you know
playlists on Spotify - you can you can
in your mind in my mind you can sit
there and you can go okay
these are gonna bang out like these are
gonna be really popping up wherever
you're playing you know and people will
still come up to and be like what is
this I look at you like you're an alien
like hey man can you play like strictly
from like 2000 to 2010 like that era of
like club music they never even tell you
that much info though what I love to do
is tell you that they don't like what
you're doing and they're doing what
would you like for me to play and
writing something - uh something good
write something different something good
something you can dance to like . hold
on every song for the most part has
rhythm and you can dance to it so let's
not use that as a criteria for the genre
of music that you want me to play
western music is well i I've said to
people I can't teach you rhythm what
would you like I have literally said
that multiple times in of course they
don't understand it but so you and you
were saying you with request you don't
you know mind them but yeah I mean it
does is you were talking about the
paintbrush thing and that's that is very
beautiful Kelly but like I think that
sometimes the requests kind of like rip
the paintbrush out of our hand and
they're like here's your sharpie just
draw what I want right yeah and
we can't not only have you just like
thrown this big old like mud clot into
our clear water of what we're trying to
like show you here we also just have the
next 20 minutes to try to recover from
what what you may have just like really
want us to play right now and in but but
so here's another thing and this is
somebody I definitely won't touch on and
this will be really good to talk with
you with you about Ryan because I was
thinking about I've been very just
trying to turn to take my whole life
that you know like trying like why did I
get into DJing why did I what am i doing
now what's gonna happen just like when I
first started and it was electronic
music for sure like I I wasn't against
anything else but I was just so hooked
by electronic music I did I had blinders
on for any other music guy super loved
hip-hop always I would listen to it
stuff but I didn't want to DJ I'm just
gonna like do the electronic thing and
what I had done at the beginning was
like I took my I mean I'm even just
gonna say like a little bit of high
school popularity I'm gonna say that and
then I and then I sort of thrown parties
and started like book in the homies and
then so we have like these huge outdoor
if we don't know if we told you about
these like these outdoor renegade yes
kill and I've chatted about it multiple
yeah I mean we'd have like a few hundred
people like are upwards ones we're like
drop the address the day of and we have
like 500 people out there or am like
these are totally illegal and terrible
but this was years ago but but so what
it was is these are my you know my
parties to me I have all the boys with
me like I give myself the headlining
slot I play sure I want people love me
of course because I just put myself in
the golden spot right but then I started
like okay well this is taking up a crazy
moment I'm gonna start making some money
for it I started getting like we played
my Barbie play at the club started
playing clubs in Seattle and we did
a couple events in Vancouver Portland um
but it's funny because what I started
with this thing is I can play whatever I
want I'm DJ Chronos people love
what I play and they did and they let's
do it my my online presence met the same
thing my people came to my shows they
listened to those same mixes later I
loved it started doing more bar gigs and
start realizing that like Jake rinds
isn't isn't super popular everywhere
Jake Cronus isn't super popular
everywhere you have people in this bar
that I'm playing for don't give a
about what I'm playing and what I'm
doing with my fingers and how cool it is
that I'm actually writing songs and then
it's like it was this weird thing where
I was like oh man I got momentum in this
direction I didn't realize where I was
putting myself yeah and so all of a
sudden I'm like this confident playing
for 500 people who love me right
and then I'm in a bar at 10 p.m. and an
old guy is just like screaming at me
with his finger in my face because I
didn't play Johnny Cash or some
right and so it's just huge dynamic
right so we see deejaying disc jockey
DJing like it's the most broad
terminology ever but like we kind of not
only get confused ourselves I think but
like the audience gets confused like
they don't know the difference between
the guy that hired out their wedding and
Skrillex right they have no idea and I
think like what I was saying there with
that example of me like you know I was
like the cool guy the headliner the like
I have this sound I was more of an
artist and less of a worker you kind of
get into these environments where you're
playing at a bar you're playing in a
club and you want to be kind of your own
artist you want to be an individual you
want to show these people like hey I I
don't know how to explain it to you in
words but like I know things about music
I can show you a story in this musical
journey tonight if you - let me right
but that doesn't cross well with giving
people what they want when you're hired
for a gig so well I think that I think
one of the the terms that I've that I've
tried to live by two is two for you and
one for me and so when you're mixing you
know when you're playing the songs so
you just you're not losing your total
integrity because I mean you got a gig
you know if you're gigging and you're
like okay I got to do this you know two
or three times a month you know how to
be able to have supplement income or to
be able to just feel whole whatever it
is you just don't want to be a soulless
jukebox like you just don't want to show
up and play the top 20 songs and just
call it a day and collect your check and
I don't think anybody has ever got into
DJing to be able to do that so I think
that the one there's two ways that I've
kind of been coming back into DJing
because any time that you leave for an
extended period of time I call it the
itch you get the itch right you're like
you're like I don't you know what I need
to take a break this isn't for me
you know I I don't I want to go explore
other areas whatever it might be life
family artistry right and and you'll get
down the road you'll be like okay I got
to go do this again because this is who
I am so for me getting back into it you
know I'm I'll be 41 in April I mean I'm
I'm very much a veteran of doing this
I'm not a young buck and
and I still get it I'm like I want to go
DJ tonight you know and so what I've
done is now that I'm older I I have to
absolutely be selective and so when I go
out and do a gig so if I'm heading over
to Bend like in February it'll be a two
for you one for me meaning two for the
crowd one for me
or how do I find a unique remix for this
song that isn't too far out there like
it the integrity of the song still gets
played and people recognize and they can
still sing along and say oh this song
right and so recognized enough but then
the flip side is then is like what
you're talking about you through events
that people knew what they were getting
when they showed up right and so you can
put yourself the center of attention and
and and be able to play what you want to
play so there's there's definitely two
sides you know keeping your integrity
with the to free them one for you but
then you just you just do a night you
know and I've been to listen to a lot of
podcasts with older DJ's that that's
what they were starting to get back into
rather than doing this you know playing
the hottest clubs type stuff they go
back to their home city and they mean
big cities like Seattle in San Francisco
and LA and they start doing their own
nights they're like ok I want to be a
creator of music right and I want to
deliver it to people that are interested
in that and so they start doing their
own nights to be able to do that rather
than ok I gotta do four gigs this month
and you know I gotta do them at these
bars that you got guy in the corner
yelling at playing Johnny Cash right so
for the record I love Johnny Cash but oh
yeah Johnny Cash is great it just
doesn't mix that well with Skrillex
right it does no it does you just have
to try our des no no that that is super
interesting I really like that
perspective because I guess that is kind
of what I at the beginning same thing as
I started I was like I want to do this
this town we're in the small town where
we're at
probably heard a million times you
listen to podcast but we're currently in
Castle Rock and we're talking about the
towns of Kelso Longview area anyway
which is where a little bit a little bit
more hour north of Portland and you know
two hours south of Seattle so we have
this small-town dichotomy
um but it's weird right like it's it's
it's interesting like you you guys have
played Seattle Portland it's like just
some extent like it it's weird having
the small town right next to the to the
big town but it is cool being like like
finding your own lane and like digging
it in and like okay like there's some
people here who like this but like let's
like find really who they are right so
you can kind of put yourself on this so
I any like listeners and young listeners
and young DJ's and young artists
musicians put your cell phone put
yourself on dude like if you want to
start throwing parties start getting
your homies together and in pull like
what do you have you have a light cool
my other friend has a green light
we'll get your blue light we'll put
those behind us go do that two lights
right you got any friends and speakers
my aunt has a speaker right get it
together pool together that's what we
did and we am I mean you know try to get
some some legal stuff going on your end
don't don't do everything illegally in
the woods but yeah yeah throw in your
own nights we're actually that's
something that we're all doing we're all
kind of older and we all have our gigs
here and there we all DJ in like
different ways I have my more audio
engineering Kelly's still always in
school he's always like it constantly
Michael I became more of a wedding DJ
yeah yeah right right yeah I think just
yeah yeah putting yourself on do you
want to talk about wedding DJ and Kelly
do you want to like go in the contrast
between that because that's something
that I think should be explained what's
the big contrast there Oh wedding DJing
is is way much different than bar DJing
or even DJing as yourself
what wedding DJing is kind of one of
those things where you go into and
you're trying to make these people's day
like you're the like one of the most
integral parts of that person's wedding
so you're there with it's you're there
with their family and it's you know you
you play very PG music and it's not
heavy mixing it's more of just playing
what what these people know and it's not
heavy mixing like I said I don't want to
mix it they just they want the full song
right
what makes anything like not in between
two songs not mashing yeah you're not
mashing you're not you're not really
doing much of that you're just trying to
set a mood and trying to keep the the
wedding party moving that's what I think
weddings are really are and yes it is
about the music but it's more of
creating that time for them sort of so
well there's a I think there's a
different level of I'm not gonna say
professionalism but there's there's a
different amount of stress I mean I I
honestly haven't done a wedding in 10
years I purposely I get asked all the
time it's funny I'm you know be a
nightclub and people are just going nuts
and you know playing all these remixes
and they're having the time of their
life right and they're like oh I got a
wedding come up I want this guy right
and they'll come up to me I'm like you
don't want me at your wedding because
it's gonna be like this and you'll be
dancing but your family's not gonna be
into it your buddy will hate but but
when I was doing when I was gigging with
with weddings regularly its or corporate
events special events class reunions
parties you know it's stressful because
like weddings it's one of the most
important days of their life and you
know a speaker goes out or you're late
or you don't play the right type of
music I've had instances where you know
you guys might laugh but you know baby
got back right so sir mix-a-lot which is
a classic hip hop you know even ten
years ago it was classic right and so
wedding party will come up we want to
hear this song and we're like all right
that's safe right that's a safe song
right and you play it and then the mom
and dad that are paying for the wedding
come up to you know where you're DJing
and they're like what are you playing
why are you playing this and and the
dance Horse packed and the wedding
reception is just having a great time
right and so it's that it's that weird
that weird dynamic of appeasing the
person that's paying you so
traditionally it's been you know mom dad
with the bride right um - the the bride
and the groom who are honestly stressed
out most important day of their life
they've been building up to this moment
and they
want to have a good time they don't want
to think about what songs play there's
one dance to be over here right right
and so it's it's definitely a different
stress level than playing like you know
a nightclub gig yeah it's do this is
huge it's for me I'm I mean I've
recently stepped out of weddings it's
what I actually they're there
emotionally I'm very like it's hard for
me to like I pick up on a lot of
emotions like that no I you know when
it's in the same way any of us do I'm
sure but so if it's like if I mess this
up this is not just like oh man they're
not gonna want to hire me and they're
not gonna recommend me they're not gonna
but when I'm thinking like if I mess
this up I'm gonna ruin this woman's
wedding it's the most important day of
her life
I'm breading her whole like I'm putting
these people their most important day in
their life on my shoulders right
honestly I bet you that you guys do the
same thing in certain ways too yeah oh
it's it's it's something that is super
huge in and I think that like a lot of
like the drunk uncles that weddings are
very unforgiving like they're very again
I'm particularly a sensitive dude I can
usually take some banter but sometimes
man when I'm I'm thinking so in depth
about about not ruining this this
woman's wedding and trying to do the
absolute best that I can like I'm just a
thin piece of glass and I don't realize
I've had weddings where I'm just like
I'm so good I'm like okay things are
going so well and I'm like some drunk
uncle comes up and he just so
mean to me that I'm just like on the
verge of tears afterwards yeah oh man
I'm like man I didn't realize how much I
had on my shoulders but it just started
to crack so um but yeah so like so I've
stepped out of weddings not that it's
like like just because people are super
mean and I'm super sensitive this is
just because I as far as enjoyment and
what I want to be doing I've just been
able to like make my money with my audio
engineering stuff but but I mean
weddings can be fun okay they can be a
blob I think it's totally like super fun
right and if you can get that vibe going
you know and if you're going from you
know Beatles twist and shout and
everybody is just going nuts on the
dance floor I mean it's a totally
different energy level than you know a
nightclub gig unless there are dry
wedding dry weddings suck I mean I've
never successfully done dry wedding I
have not um oh wait I have performed
obviously provides services
the dry wedding but it was everybody
sitting eating dinner and then you're
just trying to hit the bangers yeah and
nobody's dancing know what to do it
wasn't the one that I did was not bad I
only did one it was honestly good like
after the at the end of night there like
that was amazing right it's wonderful
I'm like nobody on the floor right you
know what's funny is I was kind of
comparing it's like how weddings
typically go though honestly at the end
I just felt bad I was like I wish that I
didn't like I'm not willing to do this
because I just have my one flat rate cuz
I have to do it that way it's so much
but I was like I wish I didn't charge
you this much because I feel like what
what what you got wasn't like I give
people so much more for the same price
you know you don't want to know yeah
yeah I was super apprehensive about
doing what it it's not first like people
would always ask me they'd go do you do
weddings
and I'd be like oh man like yes I have
done weddings and it's just it is a lot
of stress the I think the hardest part
about weddings is the processional like
the down and back is like the most
nerve-wracking thing I think I remember
it was like 9:00 like 95 out and I just
remember Oh Jordan coming up to me he's
like dude are you okay and I did a I did
a double set up which is your you do set
of speakers out by like the the altar
and then you'll have like another set of
speakers like where'd all the dancing is
going yeah
the reception really hard to do by
yourself and I'm I'm just I'm just there
just sweating bullets cuz a I'm nervous
I don't want to I don't want to mess
this up and be it's just super hot out
so as soon as we got through to the
processional it's like I could kind of
take a a brat path who like we're
through that like now now the fun part
begins and yeah like just what and like
what you saying you have those drunk
uncles who come up I had a remember some
guy came up to me wanted Van Halen's
eruption I'm just going through like the
normal wedding stuff right interruptions
like this like three
long guitar solo by Eddie Van Halen and
it's it's a great so I mean I love that
song but it's like not wedding
appropriate it's like and so finally I
caved and I was just like alright I'll
play it and it's just this ridiculously
awesome guitar so and yeah so I played
it and I'm like okay we can move on from
that and he comes back like five minutes
later played again no I never also so
like I've also been at the mercy of a
five-year-old once to where that'll get
you to yeah I think they give the kids
the power they take it yeah
I've and here's the thing when I get
hired for for weddings you're hiring me
to basically curate this thing like it's
it's not gonna be one of those things
where I want someone like because people
think that people think that if they go
up to the bride and they convinced the
bride hey bride play this song because
the DJ is not playing it which is a
terrible thing to do there's other
things that the the brightest worrying
about like I don't know the absurdity of
how often that happens I'm pretty
surprised don't know if that happens
often around you guys but people have
like if I've said no they have gone to
the bride or groom what do you write an
eight-year-old also does that like you
won't play my song right yeah so so this
kid he wanted like Five Finger Death
Punch
and I'm just like no we're not playing
ha ha ha no and he goes and gets his dad
and his dad comes up to me he's like hey
can you play this song I'm like no he's
like well I'm gonna go tell the bride
I'm just like please don't do that and
he went and got the bride and the bride
came over and she's hammered and so
she's just inebriated already and she
goes hey can you play the song I'm just
like I'm not the mercy of an
eight-year-old who has terrible I
shouldn't say that who who doesn't
understand like this is a well an
eight-year-old should not have that much
power of course the
and he's 8 years old right he doesn't
have that power he also shouldnt have a
driver's license that's why we're safe
on the road right gosh like could you
imagine if you still listen to the music
you did when you're 8 know what I listen
to when I was 8 I was listening to like
biggie smalls I mean I guess no not all
of us were that cool but yeah I would
get into like I you know I at 8 I was
very sheltered so I was listening to
like the Commodores like 60s and 70s
music R&B black jazz that's the type of
music that my folks listen to and so
that's what I grew up on you know so at
eight gosh that would have been me know
early 90s so and then you know my my mom
my dad kind of got stuck in the 60s or
70s so you know when you're talking
about deejaying diverge a little bit so
the you know you have the sphere your
musical your musical influence year so
age 16 whatever you're listening to when
you're 16 if that song or that group of
music ever comes on in a bar or
nightclub you will you will fan boy or
girl out like oh my gosh immer and so
you know for me I didn't really have
that it was all I was always listening
to like I said 60s and 70s R&B rock that
kind of stuff so it's interesting you
get in those mixing moments and you look
out in the crowd you like okay if I want
to hit home with some of these people
and you're like okay you know what were
they listening to when they were 16 if
they're 26 so that's 10 years ago you
know so you do all that type of you know
thought process on it but yeah I don't
know why an eight-year-old would be
doing heavy metal at a wedding and the
crummy thing is that as soon as you play
that then the entire mood that you've
set for the entire night is now
destroyed which is great when you are
trying to reset it right like right
sometimes you could just throw it like
you know like out of nowhere you just
throw some song that we can sing out
loud even right even if it's a slow song
right reset it but when that happens
when it's like just song that's
completely out so jarring yeah yeah and
people know what to do and it's funny
because we you know the squeakiest wheel
gets the
right that's what it always is with I
mean really everything but but the
person that always comes up it's hard
for for me anyway for a lot of us
because it's hard to to tell them like
hey you're not everyone right like what
you're saying right like cool like I
like I cool man like I trust okay I
believe you that this is gonna fill the
dancefloor but it's also my job and I've
been doing it for a very long time so I
think I know more than you right in like
what you can't say that you of course
you can't say that to the person that's
coming up - what weddings are are
different Reid - like yeah oh so I'm
gonna try and be Jake for a bit here
okay reading a crowd is is kind of
looking around the room seeing if people
are vibing out - what you're playing so
reading a wedding is a little bit
different because you know you have your
it's it weddings are more have a
timeline whereas like a bar doesn't when
you're you're not we're gonna do toast
we're gonna do dinner we're gonna do
first dance you're not hosting the event
right right yeah at a wedding you're
hosting the event you are the timeline
you're controlling it right so you're
not gonna just play some crazy stuff
during dinner you're like you're gonna
wanna you want dinner music and ease
into it you want yeah just and then as
kind as the night progresses you know
we're still PG but I love it when
there's weddings where it's like you
kind of look around and you're like okay
all the old people and kids gone right
and then it's like okay try it turn it
turn it into club club turn this place
into a club right right yeah well I and
I and I think some of the challenges you
have like when you play a reset song
right if you want to call it that or a
request that's been demanded by to the
wedding party now they've come over to
you the the challenging part and you can
run into this in the nightclubs too is
you play that song and it breaks the
mood and awesome somebody has to make a
decision do I want to stay or don't want
to go so at a wedding you've built this
entire vibe right and and the wedding
party's having a great time they're out
there dancing and then basically you get
demanded to play this song you play it
and now like oh hey look it's getting
late
and oh you know all we've had a little
bit too much drink so it can actually
destroy the party at that point and same
thing in a club night you like if you
get demanded you're like okay I'm way up
here the energy-wise and you and you
play this hip-hop song right that nobody
knows because they demand it off their
phone people it breaks their their mood
and then also they're saying you know
what hey let's go maybe we go find
someplace else yeah they weren't even
gonna say that right right they're
enjoying it they're having a good time
you know you as the DJ they're making
you're making money for the bar you've
created this atmosphere and then also
and you got to play this one song or you
make a mistake and you play the wrong
song and then it breaks the vibe and
then and then people basically pull up
and they're like alright well let's
let's you know let's go to this bar
let's you know we're done for the night
or whatever yeah it kind of flips that
switch and it makes them start like
going down that right yeah it's kind of
strange um so the the world of today
DJing I think of like you know like 16
you know young kids 16 year olds you
know 21 like anybody listening who's
like alright we've got some old cats
with like let's listen to this podcast
and see if we can like learn something
right nowadays dude it's so it's so
crazy different like whether whether
you're going to be like a wedding DJ
whether you're gonna like you want to
play EDM whether you want to be a
producer like knowing what lane you're
going into I think is really important
that's something that caught me off
guard that I didn't realize was like I
started building a mobile DJ business
and I didn't want to be a mobile DJ no
that was years into it and I'm like oh
oh I don't I don't want to be
up till 4:00 a.m. right I every night I
don't want to like carry all my stuff to
to this gig every Saturday you know in
in I'm not saying these are bad things
like these these are still things that I
do very much I still this is how I make
money you know but it's when I started
realizing like oh I kind of cornered
myself just like letting the the
opportunities kind of ride me into the
field Manila too so I think writing
opportunities is important but
I think when you when you don't know
much when you're starting from like zero
point as a DJ I think knowing the
difference between producing DJing
between wedding DJing between club DJing
between knowing what what the words open
format means right all these things so
someone who just loves music and we've
all had them throughout our life they're
like man I would love to teach a write
we have so many people who are they
think that they can't they're like I
don't know anything you know whatever
right like we're always I can guarantee
you we're like dude do it that's so cool
right and I show you I'm over it like
we're like yeah yeah so what do you guys
think like the starting point
what would you say anybody's want to get
into it well I think it goes from what
you said was that you have to love music
first oh yeah and you have to and
honestly I mean you don't have to love
like every single genre but you have to
be a lover of music and I think it
doesn't matter which lane you pick out
whether or not it's mobile or wedding or
nightclub or straight genre nightclub
meaning you know you're a hip-hop night
club DJ or you're EDM night club DJ you
just have to love music and be or build
or appreciate it like oh I like that
sound you know or be able to recognize
you know I don't know I mean one one
thing that I that I wish that I would
have got more into and hopefully you
know I can make time to is producing
because I love I love music that
sonically complex but at the same time
can be simple and so it you know I don't
like all hip-hop but I enjoy listening
to hip-hop because I can pick out
different pieces I'm like oh that's cool
that's cool right I would say even to my
former self or even to a young producer
it doesn't happen all at once
like you're you're gonna suck first for
a long time I sucked for 15 years I'm
just gonna be honest I thought I was I
thought I was good whether that's like
DJing or producing like you're gonna go
through that phase where you're just
gonna suck like the music you make just
is terrible like you're trans
are terrible who like music selections
terrible selections right but Brian yeah
you're right you have to be a lover of
music and it has to be something you do
it's like even from the podcasts about
Spencer like he was like you have to do
it like uh-huh you can't you can't just
be like oh I'm gonna I want to lift
weights so I'm gonna go to gym once yeah
I know look at him I'm gonna talk about
I meet everybody about him but I'm not
getting ready because I haven't touched
him yet but look at that i'ma look at ya
so I mean it's with anything it's
shooting basketballs it's doing math
problems you have to do it you have to
put that work in and it's it's sitting
in your bedroom
for hours really I I'm pretty sure I
like annoyed the crap out of my
roommates up in Bellingham just playing
like all the time the hours and hours
and days and days you probably just wear
it headphones because and it's it's so
enthralling and that's the thing is is
you know if you're like oh I want to be
a DJ but if these things don't spark you
I'm not saying there's a certain amount
of hours that you need in but like just
follow that intuition man if you do have
a drive to not hang out with a bunch of
people but you you actually just want to
be by yourself and make some music and
you want to mix some stuff and that's
more exciting man follow that that's
right oh that's so okay I think that
like just loving music just like you
said is the perfect that's how you get
into it that's like like as much as
again bringing back the gatekeeper thing
as much as you're like I don't think
that like I just like music I don't even
know what I don't even know what a C
minor is whatever right well I've been
DJing and I've now made an audio
engineer degree out of it I've 91 junior
degree I travel the freaking u.s. like
making money and I enjoy it and I have
like really cool friends who I could
talk about DJing with on might not get
like knowing how these microphones work
started from me saying oh what music I
think cascade is cool yeah you know
right like so so I think just starting
with I love this and then just working
at it just put some headphones in and
just get to work and like in afterwards
afterwards once you kind of start
getting better
mm-hmm that's when it gets fun mm-hmm
like when you're ready to I mean you
know I Brian do you get butterflies
before you go on a show every single
time you type
every time it doesn't make sure it
doesn't yeah it doesn't matter and it's
not butterflies like oh I'm gonna do a
bad job it's important to you so you
know you have to love music yeah and it
has to be important to you if you just
want to you know show up and I'm not
picking on you but because I've done it
too but be the headliner and you know
and have eyes on you and and not put any
work like just pick the top ten beep
port songs and play them in Miravalle oh
my gosh is great it might not be for you
cuz you're gonna get burned out real
quick mm-hmm because people gonna move
on you know or or it's gonna get old you
know you talk about all the different
things that DJing has done for you you
know for me it got me into IT technology
IT technologies and getting to where I'm
at with my career and doing some really
cool complex things with computers and
and and all that all the intricate like
installing stuff that you do yeah I'm so
crazy but I mean that started from you
saying I like music yeah I like music I
can do it better than them this guy
that's doing do you guys think that like
cuz that is super cool if you think
about like the ultimate like creation
entreprenuer like it's like you don't
even so DJing I feel like you could
really start it's you know guitar
playing you're like I love music I'm
gonna tar it'sit's quite a while before
you like I mean you're just like make
something like you you hate everything
that comes out of your fingers phrenic
seven months with those are like we do
Jing I feel like you can really get you
know I'm within the first couple days
for me I was like dude that was so cool
I want to call my friends and tell them
and joke you know so it is cool like
just getting it just start mixing a
couple songs there's all these cheap
mixers nowadays right yeah well and
that's that's the cool thing with I mean
it's it's good about so you know as as
an old dog veteran all these people now
are DJing right and like everybody's a
DJ that was you know from like 2010 to
2015 everybody was a DJ and the price of
entry is so much cheaper you know you
can go get a hundred dollar controller
you know with a cheap computer that you
find off of Craigslist and
you know a downloaded library or Spotify
or whatever it is right and you know the
old dog in me is like well they haven't
put in the dues right you know I haven't
packed like two milk crates full records
and you know that I didn't have to spend
seven or fifty bucks um they haven't
slept in their car well yeah whatever
whatever it is right you know we're
playing a gig for 50 bucks and a bar tab
you know they haven't like put their
dues in but the same time it's exciting
for me because it's like anybody that
comes up to me like hey I'm gonna learn
how it's DJ hey here's what you do go by
this hundred dollar controller right
like if it's not for them it's okay they
haven't like put a bunch of money into
it and have it be like oh I spent all
this money and people are you know I'm
not into it and so it's really it's
actually pretty exciting that everybody
has the accessibility to be able to do
what 25 years ago me was a challenge to
get into so it's cool because when you
find something that you love you want
everybody to like go along with it right
like have you heard this or have you
listened this or have you seen this or
every diamond I don't think you this is
really cool right
and and you know so it's exciting for me
to have everybody and their brother be
able to like my kids you know I'm like
said I'm older so I got you know a ten a
nine year old for them to be able to not
play with dad's equipment cuz I have
expensive equipment that $100 mixer and
like go mix go figure out what you like
I'll go buy whatever music you want to
be able to listen to you right and they
aren't quite there yet but I'm hoping
that they will be so it's it's cool for
me to be able to like I said see all of
these people that want to get into it
have the opportunity to that's a a big
part of my core is opportunity for
people to be able to experience things
that are awesome so I have no clue where
else going with that but I think it's
cool that that you know a DJ starting
out now has a lot more accessibility to
the technologies to be able to build it
into something that's way more and trust
me when you start DJing you think that's
that's all you want to do and that's
cool and if you stick with that
path there's nothing wrong with that
right I mean there's perils with being a
full-time DJ but you know we can talk
about that and maybe another podcast but
it's but it's you know if you're
starting out and you and your DJ then
that's great
but there's so many different things
that you can learn from DJing event
planning and marketing and promotions
and audio engineering and social like
how to interact with people in stressful
situations where you're sober and
they're super intoxicated right or
they're in crisis mode or whatever it is
I mean there's so many things that that
you can learn being a DJ that you
wouldn't think that had anything to do
with teaching you know right yeah
yeah that's it's crazy it's again it
just opens up so many doors like it's
it's cool to think I mean cuz I never
even it's not like a lot of times we
think we have to have our job title or a
decision figured out before we even
start it right we're like I'm choosing
to be a DJ that's who I am now that's
what I represent that's what I'm gonna
do going forth but again you can just
say I like music and just point out any
of like these apps these little programs
these whatever and just dink around I
was thinking like even as a DJ we listen
to music a lot differently than other
people listen to music mm-hmm like even
when we show up to other clubs like Jake
Jake and I went to tube a couple times
tubes a club down in Portland that has
phenomenal DJs there oh it's just and
it's teeny tiny it's like it's like I
think we did 50 people right and they
got a hundred people and oh yeah the way
that it's built in there like when it
sounds right there when they have the
sound tight to that there has been time
was too loud but it sounds super tight
in there those will sit there and we'll
be like whoa did you just hear that did
you hear what he just did and we'll just
we'll just sit there and and we're not
nitpicking it we're just listening to it
differently or I'll go to like 45 ease
and I'll be like
oh that's that collab with this person
this person this right or I can hear
this song coming in or I can yeah you
know it's the cool thing that least in
different DJ's here some people
something that's it's totally cool to go
to clubs and just have a good time right
like me I it's a little bit of both
it's like I want to see what their what
their visuals are like you know how
they're mixing new stuff old stuff just
you know what's funny is something that
I didn't know when I started was the can
of whoop-ass I was opening up on my own
brain for every event I would go to in
the future oh yeah like I do realized
that I would I would be judging all I
thought I was just still gonna be able
to go to all my favorite shows and just
dancing around and have a good time but
instead I'm just like over analyzing
every single second everything it's like
like the second that you learned that a
tree is a tree you can't look at it be
like that's that's not drowning what
that is alright yeah because once you
know this information in with with the
music world you keep well and I and I
interview you know we go back to being a
chef for the night right so you know I
part of being a nightclub industry early
in my career you know front of house I'm
waiting tables and doing all that right
so when as as someone who's in the
restaurant industry a chef or whatever
you go to other restaurants and you're
analyzing everything like oh it took too
long for that food to get out or you
know this flavor profile is weird right
it's the same thing it doesn't matter if
it's an EDM show doesn't matter if it's
festival doesn't matter if it's concert
I am constantly looking at everything
and not judging it's like oh that's
really cool or you know and trying to
figure out how they did that or how they
did this not even so much the artist
piece of it but then you look at the
artist piece you're like oh yeah this
club you know in this VIP and and I've
only heard that a couple times you know
or how they're mixing I mean my mixing
style has changed greatly since I've
dough headfirst into bass music into you
know dubstep and trap and mid-tempo and
yeah and it's like okay double chops and
and it's you know all these different
techniques that to me as a straight DJ
you know meaning eight eight beats and
mixing
that's my style to see how they mix now
is is it's awesome to be able to go
experience that so yeah yeah it's
definitely frustrating for people that I
take with me to events because they
either like can you just shut up yeah
like I don't care your route you're
breaking the illusion okay it's funny
because I would I go with friends who
because there's a lot of people who are
they love the intricacies that like I
have tons of friends who don't know
anything about DJing they kind of remain
in that like everything you're saying
though I love please telling me like
because people would love to hear about
that right and majority the part like I
think if it's a girlfriend she doesn't
hear any of that at all but uh like
some of these guys when when you're
explaining it they're just like wow like
that's that's what it takes to think
that way and it's it's funny though but
it's like it just unfolds that way you
don't really try it's not like I'm not
trying to over analyze the situation
it's kind of how knowledge works you
can't you know the thing with the tree
you can't look at a book and not start
reading you know what the word say right
this is this really cool thing that I
knew that there was music there and knew
that there was like once you know how to
read know or once you know like oh you
hear that and that's this this sound
that's this key you unlock that's like a
different language right so it's it's a
different way of understanding the world
but it's cool there's even before music
there even before all the the weird
rules of music and how it works together
like DJing us its own thing still it
still writes desperately different um I
have noticed like so so I was never a
producer I didn't I don't have a music
background I am growing up I
skateboarded a lot and I listened to
everything I loved like really likes you
know punk rock rap everything I just had
an obsessed with music I didn't know
anything about I never should have quiet
class anything so learning all this was
kind of weird I feel like I would kind
of like dance around and like certain
conversations where I'd be like I'm in
front of people who are like nice good
good producers and they're saying things
that I have no idea what the the
words are coming on their mouth because
I don't know I don't have the music
background know trying to like keep up
and it's kind of funny because we think
DJing like okay so you know everything
about music you know everything about
audio engineering you are
about live events you know everything
about my sister like whatever they
there's a lot of different
compartmentalization when it comes to
teaching so as I've been mommies like
more recent years last year and a half
I've been producing more I've been kind
of like digging into my knowledge and
seeing what happens like watching less
tutorials doing more of like stop trying
to plan it just like go on to go in
front of the board and just like it's
not cry into it for four hours and
generally what comes out you know is
hugely hugely different process
producing in creating music is a night
and day difference than DJing so can we
for the average consumer who doesn't
understand like I said the difference
between wedding DJ can we like talk
about the difference being like a
producer and a DJ can we clear that up
for sure yeah yeah so producer is
somebody who pretty much sits on
computer and you know they'll they'll
use a what's called a DAW a digital
audio workstation shop workspace a
station or space works it's enough it's
a doll and you might hear Jay karai talk
about like certain ones like Elton free
lips some people used reason a lot of
people use logic and these are all
different different dots there's one's
not better than the other
I'd say Pro Tools is more for live more
like live instruments and whereas like
you know more DJ's are probably more
like Ableton or logic he's got confusing
you said DJ's who like me are producers
producers sorry it's a confusing thing
so so producing is like is like making
the music right yes and engaging is it's
funny because you we sound like we don't
do anything when you say in the sense
but producers make me as it can we play
other people's music correct yes I don't
know how to explain that to where but I
don't sound like word but but you can
have a DJ that will remix a song right
so or they'll make an edit and so
they'll rearrange different pieces of it
and they're using the same tools that
the producer is
so it you know producers they make the
music and then they get into into a
point where they start getting asked to
perform that music live you know whether
or not they've pre-recorded the the mp3
the file and they're doing what we do
which is as a DJ just hitting play you
know and mixing the song in so it's the
the word DJ has been used
interchangeably over the last ten years
now because producers have rightfully so
in my opinion have come forward and
they're like well we want to get paid
for performing our music to just like a
band you know and you know so you have
like Calvin Harris Calvin Harris is a
producer okay he produces his own music
but he gets bucco buckos going to mega
clubs in Vegas and around the world
to actually play that music as well so
you know producer and DJ are
interchangeable in the fact I think one
way meaning a producer can be a DJ but a
DJ in a traditional sense isn't a
producer right right yeah that's like I
said like I've always made I've always
made edits and that's the thing is like
people like hey man you should make a
remix of this song that's like I've
gotten that sentence yeah because people
think that you're cool they've
experienced like I don't know anything
about this stuff but I know that when I
heard you play it was super cool dad
right I'm right and I like this song and
I think that if you did it in your style
it would sound cool so they know that
but you know and I make edits to where
you know you mash up different things
you have different samples and you know
mashing up is even just you take more
than one song or the elements of a
strong instrumental in an acapella and
combine them together in your own way
yeah good I would say like there there
are producers out there that you would
even know is are is them on a different
track like it would be like a oh who's a
popular female singer
dual Eva yeah do live like you'd think
that like oh like she has just some
person in the background who makes her
all her music well turns out like nine
times out of ten like it might be Diplo
or it might be cashmere cat right yeah
and these are like big DJ's that people
have heard right names but you would
never know it's them and it's like whoa
is is that cashmere cat what's going on
or even like Cali Cali was I think there
was when a black panther came out there
was like the guys who were making the
the soundtrack to or the theme music to
Black Panther they actually used a
Callie like like bass head yeah it's so
cool they would they it just they were
shown in the interview and Callie always
you know Marx's you know Callie snare
you Callie this alright whatever it is
and so there it is he goes holy crap
like my kick drum I made is actually in
in in the black feather wait can you
back up a little bit the kick drum he
made can you explain that a little bit
so that's that's a producing side he
collie as a producer he produced so when
he makes a kicked run he has these these
sub programs let's say within the DA
within a digital audio workstation and
you can have their their synthesizers
there's all these crazy when the
listener if you've seen you know all
these crazy knobs there's now the same
thing they do all those same things but
it's on your computer it's digital you
know so when he says he makes his own
sagar his own kick it's like he's like
making these frequencies and combining
you know modulators and all these
effects different whatever to to make a
sound so he's saying he put out there
he's like hey here's my kick and it
sounds like you've ever it is and then
other people downloaded that right in
their house Amma right and they and they
put it in they dragged and dropped it
and they put it into their beat pad and
they made a song and that song ended up
a black panther so that's that's what
you're saying like that's so crazy right
yeah yeah and so that's what like I
think when the average consumer hears
producer or DJ they don't really
understand how complex it is and I think
that what should have happened is
so fast but we need different
terminology I think is what should have
happened here as it is confusing as
right but but yeah I think like getting
to know the difference between DJ and
producer a lot of times like me for
example I've been a DJ it's gonna be
getting more few did forever but now
that I'm producing my own music I have a
plan I'm starting to do like some more
MIDI stuff in my live sets I have a plan
of like bringing in vocalists for stuff
that I arrive ok I write like the
instrumentals of dink around on the
piano keys and then I'll write the
lyrics but I'm gonna release a song with
someone else singing it but it's I wrote
it I wrote the instrumental but I don't
particularly think that my voice is
gonna make this long it's great right B
and you're doing the arrangement with
the overall track right yeah and so in
so looking forward in the future it's
gonna be again the same confusing loop
right it's like I am a DJ I'm known as
this or whatever but this is my
producing also it's not me it's someone
else he me it's right this confusing
DICOM well I made a good example so
nitty-gritty ok nitty-gritty he's famous
right now for doing these tic toc videos
where he just walks around and like he
gets different sounds right he did
Walgreens one which was hilarious he's
walking through Walgreens and he picks
up like a little plastic guitar and goes
ding and he's recording all the sounds
right and then he and then he puts in
but a lot of people don't realize that
so bad bunny right bad bunny had 200
mile-per-hour which was actually
co-produced with Diplo as well and so
nitty-gritty actually has a Latin Grammy
because that song won a Grammy and he's
he made some of the instruments and then
Diplo put his name on it but Diplo and
nitty-gritty didn't sing it's a bad
bunny song right and so it's it's it's
amazing to have like all of these like
if you if you look at sicko mode there's
like 30 or 35 people that are credited
on it I'm so glad you brought that I
don't know if it's 35 I have to look at
the Wikipedia yeah it's a ton it's
it's crazy so I was reading an article
on yeah look it up Kelly but it's it's
so that song is so sampled that there's
yeah I got pulled off YouTube as long as
under five seconds I'm Gucci I might
learn the copyright laws I've learned
those on Soundcloud pretty well yeah so
so all of the samples and all of the the
arrangements the notes everything is
everybody was credited on it which you
know that was a big a song of 2018 right
you team yeah
or mo Bamba or my mom or Bamba that one
was they don't came out Nord see that's
the thing a lot of these trends in music
are super weird I the more I like to
learn about society and like all the
culture stuff I'm like man I don't think
we actually like these songs I think
that we're just being told like that we
it yeah like a lot of times has it been
more detached like the last again year a
lot of the pop music that I used to
really like I'm like oh like I was just
I was just doing my job and like
regurgitating it yep yeah didn't like
Old Town Road classic case dude right I
think Old Town Road only is only popular
because it was on tick tock yeah much
yeah and it's little kids with
smartphones man right well yeah yeah
that may control it's weird because
little kids with smartphones so so
that's the thing with social media
that's new that's sending music in
different ways thanks let me see that
yeah there's a ton of people were just
sick of mode it's it's like projecting
us into into weird things I heard this
thing on Instagram they're talking about
you know getting rid of the likes on
Instagram yeah and they are diving into
that and they're like I heard maybe this
Gary Vee talked about how as an artist
so say you create you have zero
followers you have five pieces of art
and they're just like the most intuitive
they're all very different but you're
like a wide-ranging artist and they're
all five different very important pieces
of you like that you somehow got to some
conclusion to make these intricate art
well number one and two they don't
nobody really likes us number three that
has 500 videos number four that has
17,000 views number five nothing and so
if these are different kinds of arts
you're number three number four you're
like these are what people like
apparently so that's what I'm gonna do
right but now you have other four parts
of who you are maybe or who you are
trying to explore this thing you're
trying to commute
to the world through art that have now
been like you know it's not many folks
in those because people don't like those
well what if those people who like those
photos those whatever I said that
whatever number are all eight-year-old
kids would tick-tock right right so you
just curated your creation you know from
your soul as a human whatever this means
you just curated it based off of you the
likes that you got right right so I feel
like that is a little a little bit
different I things like music is is
we're seeing that with music but I will
say that's just popping music I like we
all listened did not just a popular
music right there's plenty of
underground music that's not known in
all these genres that is just
there I mean it's when you really think
about and it goes back to accessibility
you know when you when someone a
producer 30 years ago 25 years ago you
need to have a full studio we were
talking about analog and digital mixers
earlier you know you'd have this whole
stack of analog equipment then you have
your mixer in front of it and then you'd
be able to acquire the musical
instruments to be able to you know you
either have to have produced or record
it live you know or you'd have to have
like a sound Bank or you do MIDI you
know which was garbage but the
accessibility to be able to create music
is is amazing like you could pirate
don't pirate software but you could pyar
you know your your your DAW and have a
cheap $300 laptop and produce the next
big hit you know whatever big hit is in
your mind meaning mainstream or like all
your buddies love it right so it really
leveled the playing field
oh yeah it's it's crazy I mean I'm
myself personally getting into making
edits and you know making not not
remixes you know we want to talk about
that too you know difference between a
bootleg and a remix and an edit you know
a remix is something that's licensed by
the artists yeah it's official bootleg
is you have either stumbled across the
different components for the song or or
stems or you are you know basically do
we're going to do it yourself acapella
and then remix it yourself
which is a bootleg you know you have an
edit which you're rearranging or mashing
up two different songs so it's crazy
like I said the excessive
be able to create music and yet we have
the same 20 songs that are being played
on the radio or you know Spotify or you
know any get keeps getting regurgitated
and we talk about you know all I got to
hear this song because it's the biggest
song in the world I'm like you listen to
it like 15 times already today like you
listen to it in your car on the way here
right and you're gonna you're gonna
listen to it on the way home right yeah
yeah it's funny how it goes though I
mean it a lot of times I do think it
guys does go back down to like the
gatekeeper thing people like that you
know they don't have time to dive in all
their own music tastes a lot of times
people I don't I don't think they they
think they can I don't know like it's
like let's not even think about I don't
know much about music let's just let
this play right I don't know it's cool
like seeing seeing where it's going like
you know sampled music is not new
you know everybody remake sing other
cheap people stuff adding all these
things but like I don't know what the
cap is like Kelly just showed me the the
credits on sick I'm at Travis Scott well
my try to Scott he's in it it's like
there's a hundreds of people in it you
know there's a few people in it but no
it's just interesting to see what the
future's what do you guys think so so
back in the day when there was bands
right there's much people there was
there's predictions like I remember the
Daft Punk a choreo Moroder has like this
vocal sample of like I predict that
it'll be one person on stage or
something like that what do you guys
think in 10 years where does like the
not only the bands but live just live
performances DJing bands producers what
do you think it's going 10 years yeah
even even how you said that like I think
Skrillex actually did a thing where they
had he had George Morrison from The
Doors who was like I think it's gonna be
like a bunch of machines or it's gonna
be like a tapes maybe yeah I don't know
it's music is like in this really cool
cross over stage and it's it's like who
would ever thought that Diplo would make
a song with Morgan Wallen like right as
a country artist this country are yeah
yeah and Diplo is like this you know
very urban beat kind of guy
and it's you're seeing like all these
different people like country singers
come in and doing like like EDM or even
like there's like even like rehab did a
song with Mitchell Tenpenny or did that
remix to Mitch Mitchell Tenpenny song
and it's amazing it's so good and you're
seeing I'm seeing all these different
blends of music coming together because
a lot of people are just saying screw
the rules right and I think that's
organizing there is no rules there are
no rules
yeah like I just wrote down because I
wanted to talk about it there's no such
thing as cheating when it comes to music
but what do you mean there what do you
mean there's no scenes so we were just
on you know producing music there and I
I say that there's no such thing as
cheating like well I okay I guess I have
to define this a little bit better
because you can't just go rip people off
you know you can't just go I'm gonna do
I'm gonna steal this whole track and
then just make a little name over it
yeah all right I mean you can definitely
make edits and that's that's fine
but you can't just be like mmm this is
mine now yeah you'll get caught yeah so
what I wanted to say there's no such
thing as cheating like when you make
music and you're just sir now and you go
to you hear a beat loop or you see a lip
or a beat loop that's a bar as long
you're like gosh I really like this beat
I'm gonna I'm gonna take this beat and
I'm gonna put my own guitar over at
something or something and people are
like well I feel like I'm cheating
because that's not something I made
yeah but yet it's still not cheating in
a way because it's like you're not um
it's it goes back to like well I didn't
I didn't pick up the drum stick and hit
the drum and recorded it or I didn't
skin the the sheep to make this drum or
I didn't write I'd like where does it
stop yeah
I and now I'm a sheep farmer yeah and
not a producer right yeah no no that's
funny cuz there's this like little thing
that I think we've seen we sent in every
couple years we send this picture back
and forth you remember this it was
something along those lines like I
started thinking that making my own or
using someone else's drum samples was
cheating so I started making my own and
then it's like I started thinking that
using someone else's drum was cheating
so I started learn how to make my own
drums yeah and then before you know
you're a farmer you don't make music
anymore right that's why are you ready
dude Kelly I think that's a great point
like like thinking that you're cheating
so that's something that I have come
across lately so I am working with a ton
of bands a lot of like yeah crazy
talented dudes who where I'm just like
like I don't know what you guys are
doing and how you doing it but it's
really cool like a lot of really
talented guitar players and stuff and
something that happens sometimes it's
like nothing they do it on purpose but I
don't want to show them my because
it's it's loops its samples like because
I'm a DJ that's that's how I learned
that so that's how it is like I can't
pick up something super authentic and
it's like I have this feeling in the
back of my head that they're gonna be
like wool a little more pure than you
that's kind of a cool little beat you
got there buddy you know keeping yeah
it's funny though it's funny and they
don't do it they don't do it like they
they don't they don't actually feel that
way right it's like intuition that I
have around them but there is some times
where some of the conversations me as
someone who is on the fence or like on
this like in-between of like these
different worlds of music I think like
I'm kind of just like a foot in whatever
tour I could get it into like hearing
them speak about other people not not
like that they're talking crap like
hearing them downplay other people's
music for not being or for being loop
bass or being I'm not original or like
oh they just got those chords online
right they don't know how to actually
play those chords those things when I
hear those things from like talented
musicians it discourages me so much and
I don't want to show them anything it
actually ripped my soul out I'm like
qualm an idiot and I'm not even in your
guys's lane I'm not gonna show you what
I thought was cool it's funny like there
is no gatekeepers but we still think
that we need to like I'm not allowed to
do it this way so I think just to
summarize what you say
Kelly there's no such thing as cheating
man like you you you can create whatever
you want you can beat on your lap and
you can record that and then you can add
some effects in there you can you can
take it from your favorite song and take
the last eight bars or your
favorite song and then go from there for
five hours and see what happens right I
think it goes yeah screw the rules man
like screw the rules like I think one of
the greatest singers still alive now is
Dolly Parton easily like amazing voice
and I'm just I'm kind of wondering why
why hasn't anybody else like I don't
know if it's just because she just
doesn't want to work with anybody else
but that's totally fine Dolly Parton can
do whatever she wants but like it's like
why not get her on something that would
be so amazing like I would listen that
song like every day but it's just stuff
like that it's like why why put yourself
in or yeah screw the rules man like just
make music but you know what is cool is
in those same lanes of rules of it also
has screw the rules but you can make
your own to write so Kelly st. Onge if
you're like you know what I think that
dolly needs to be on another song and I
think that I'm decent enough to make a
song she's gonna be on like I don't know
how it's gonna happen but I'm gonna make
a song that I get Dolly Parton you know
I mean like right you can have these
little pipe dreams like if you're like
more people need to hear this you can
make that little Lane you can nudge your
own little path like start your own
little scene in your own town and it
projected out five years and see what's
what's going on you probably know you're
gonna get um we are getting up here in
length guys this is definitely something
that I would like if you're down maybe
every couple months or something we can
kind of chat on the world DJing if you
guys have any other DJ homie so we can
get this going yeah that'd be cool
I did want to if there's anything else
you guys want to interject I did want to
like talk about live shows and festivals
just I kinda want to end on a fun note
of us being in the crowd not DJs not
working me myself if we could touch on
like dude festivals outdoor music music
outside for me is like I mean again I
said at Cascade or in first on with the
gorge was like changed me like like made
me want to get into music but do you
guys have like like your alternate for
me it's festivals some people really
like massives and by massives I mean
like huge like the wamu Theatre in
Seattle
while inside some people like the more
underground some people like a hundred
people in like a dirty club like it like
were you guys out for me it's festivals
all the way has an attendee man a
festival is the most magical wonderful
feeling I've experienced yep yeah
festivals were where it's at so for me
being older I mean I've done you know I
started out with warehouse parties like
we'd get the address the night of you
know and you go until 6:00 in the
morning and you walk out sun's out you
know you're a vampire I've gone to that
to you know do club events and at 45
East and just good production and good
artists you know but I'm starting to
move into and I've done D so I've done
Bass Canyon you know those EDM style
events festivals which are great camping
I love it I'm starting to get more into
doing the immersive type festivals so
I'm queued up to go to electric forest
which I'm super stoked for I did the
that's a Michigan and then we're doing I
did Eclipse Festival which which was in
2017 so when I talk about it like an
immersive festival so merciful is going
to have for another word basically
tedtalks atom during the day they've got
yoga they've got genres of music that
you have never even heard of I mean they
have like live music they have people
that are doing live band but then they
have DJs they have producers that are
actually up there queuing their tracks
and they're you know and they're their
transitions and their instruments live
they have camping so you still get that
festival feel but going to that Eclipse
Festival lightning in a bottle is
another one that I want to hit up you
know even farther as far as going to
hopefully someday Burning Man
that's kind of where the direction that
I've been going into because I've done
the big production events million dollar
shows you know the big masses you're
like yeah this is really cool yeah you
want to rage but you know how
growing as an individual and as an adult
you know you get older and different
things are more important to you know
health and body and mind and spirit you
know going along those paths but a male
still build experiences amazing music
that we don't get to hear every day some
do yeah dude be the immersiveness of it
is I'm with you on that when you said
immersive festival I was like oh I
should have added that were definitely
like when it's all when it's all in yeah
when you're when you're there you're in
their world right no Kelly no we've been
what the fest there's magic here there's
Medicare oh wait oh wait we should we
should we don't tell that story real
quick okay we're gonna we're gonna end
on this one story from this festival
what fess thanks again guys one on this
story but this is this is DJ Tosi and DJ
Cal's we do actually all three of us
have a show together in April and I'm
not sure what day this is 18th 18th
April 18th yeah cool yeah so so we have
a show the three of us I feel like if
you're in town in Long be very good
solar star Bryan is controlling all that
he has a lot of strings and ideas and
really cool things going on there
so that'll be fun that'll be a glow
party and but anyway we can include info
on that in the comments do you feel like
yeah so Eagle a couple of info on that
in the comments on YouTube where
wherever you listen to this app but
Kelly tell me about this
transdimensional turtle or magic that
you've heard of it oh well you want the
magic or you want the translation both
real quick okay this is so good that's
what the festival is a festival and
defer defer for Organ dump down through
the dowels and amazing festival rest in
peace what the festival will miss it
they're done and it just like what Brian
said it's a immersive festival so you go
there and you show up and it's amazing
like you just feel like really good
energy they're like people are positive
people will want to talk to you into
stuff like that but so the
transdimensional turtle it came because
we inside the festival there was a
gumball machine in the woods like this
is a patent yeah it's how this place is
they're like you go walk in the woods
for a while yeah like look at a forest
photos and like think of like that kind
of like lighting and stuff in the wood
and then there's this gumball machine
and it's a mission machine so what you
do is it's like a candy egg and you get
your mission to do and Jake's mission
was I think to dust off the gumball
machine right yeah but mine was to kiss
a transdimensional turtle I'm like what
I don't even know what that means so we
we go out we go throughout our night and
its use we stayed out all night like you
can stay in in this festival like 24
hours like you can go you can take a nap
by the front stage like it's so cool
like once I'm here you here you do
whatever you want yeah it's so awesome
so I think Jake got up in the morning
Jake likes to go on walks kind of clear
his head
and he goes Kelly I found it I feel like
I ran back a campsite
I was so it was so profound because we
didn't know what was happening friend I
was probably super up when we did
tell me about like what what how like
what you're what oh yeah okay okay yes
so I was on this walk is like we were at
most and I like you know you sleep for a
few hours just the art of a festival
really and I went out and I was taking
my walk in the morning and this festival
is really cool you can go like you like
the front gates are like you just kind
of wait for the dude as you're walking
and it's like if you're on our property
you can go in now right it's so sick so
in the morning I'm like walking through
the woods there's a few people here and
there you walk past like a yoga class
right there is I don't think there was a
music playing at this time they did have
music going in the morning but you could
start to hear like the camp's throughout
the area there's thousands of people
here and walking through the woods in
the way I'm like not even like on the
path or anything I literally see this
little thing and I take a glance and I
look closely and it's like this little
metal
I think somebody must have made it maybe
yeah and it is a transdimensional turtle
like a little metal dude just out in the
woods yeah with like diamond eyes and
way yeah hat like you want I shouldn't
post like I should post like the picture
of me kissing it because we actually is
right so the tears that we went we found
we kept I found it again and
to kiss it so I'll post it in the
comments yeah yeah definitely do it uh
yeah so Jake Jake found he was like
Kelly I found it dude like we you know
and I was like oh my gosh like yeah way
like ran back and like we hate excuse me
we gotta kiss this we gotta get in here
but yeah yeah the so so the other thing
there with imagine there's magic here I
just
immersive festival which is it's really
something else you know you feel like
you know we hear about Bernie men we
hear about all these places and I think
the outside consumer is like that is
some crazy-ass and I am NOT that's
right I'm not going I think that that's
kind of a lot of the point you know a
lot of the point of Burning Man is I
don't know what it is now and I've never
been myself but it's kind of like this
it's Burning Man like it's the Society
of like whatever you're normally used to
doing set it on fire and see what the
comes out right I think a lot of
these vessels in the immersive ones like
man the amount of times that I'm just
stone-cold sober dancing around my arms
flailing around like a little just a
eight-year-old kid like you just feel
like this whole you know well and it's
an escape I mean yeah right yeah they're
there bunch of other people who are just
like you you dance around and someone
else notices that you dance around
they're like hey you're awesome I love
you right now and most of this that the
last thing will end on here is we were
out playing this was it a register like
a muddy river look at old school cash
registers yeah watch like beat machine
yeah this old school cash register it's
again in the woods it's standing up I
may have photos of that as well in like
we walked up to it and you start hitting
these buttons but it's hooked to a MIDI
controller
no speaker it's awesome okay so they
program like that do you boy you know
it's like almost like Mario sounds and
if you hit the right combination of
buttons the register opens and it's like
this thing that's like you don't know
like you have to like we're playing it
from for five minutes at least before
they register it we didn't even know
that was the thing yeah we're just
jamming out and there was there was some
sort of like there was a candy that
Kelly was just talking about or
something like right before he was
something about some candy that he
really particularly wanted like a
certain flavor even and anyway we this
thing comes out we hit the right
combination and it opens yeah and in
there is this candy that Kelly was just
talking about we had like like this
can't like the flavor everything
yeah long conversations 84 and we write
what and then some dude
walks up behind us and we're in the
woods he walks up behind us see what
leans in between Kelly now I can move in
he goes away like I mean we probably
high-fived and hug for like a half hour
but yeah let's do it so what if that was
what the fasten do for organ immersive
festivals are I think we're all kind of
an ingredients on that but yeah guys
let's let's go ahead and round it up our
times getting getting along here one
more time Kelly and Brian thank you guys
yeah I appreciate you having us
that's awesome do some more of these
cheers guys
you